all right thank you rich for joining the
solution raising
we schedule this not in our my usual
solution raising time is it
the same time but on wednesday and uh
it's a different topic every week but
then when i find a topic that
um inspires me something i want to do
than reaching out to one person and
saying hey what time works for us and
then
putting it out to the rest of the
community in the universe special
edition
yeah so today we're talking about the
self-help industry so we spend roughly
15 minutes but we might move on sooner
because there's only two of us
talking about what the self in help
industry currently looks like
what we like about it what we don't like
about it maybe our personal journey if
you want to share that
uh just sometimes it's a bit of a vent
and sometimes it's you know
a beautiful story so absolutely
um yeah go ahead whenever
you yeah so you're welcome to share or i
can share i have
definitely issues with the self-help
community at the moment and so
um go ahead rich i was gonna say let me
hear you i want to hear yours and i can
kind of bounce off of mine
all right sounds good um i am part of a
family that's very
self-help oriented so we've went through
the cycles of like tony robbins and
creates a culture of
ableism in my mind it's like if you're
not at this level then you're failing
and i look at people like tony robbins
and i think they offer something to the
world and at the same time we don't
do it in a scientific way we don't take
a thousand people put it through
them through his course and be like okay
who succeeds and who doesn't instead we
put them through the course and like
anything with business
it's like he gets to pick the top one
percent and be like look the system
works
and so people are mortgaging their
houses to be able to go to these events
and even if you use some of we know each
other from a different self-help person
who recently had a falling from grace
and
really time and time again this keeps
happening in my life where it's like
okay i
don't even think i hold them on a
pedestal and then they fall off and i'm
like oh no i was actually holding on a
pedestal
but there just seems to be
a weirdness in this space where i think
people get into it for beautiful reasons
they want to help people
but then they set up their brand and
they set up their business and if
they're successful at
it they then
can't grow because they're like money is
dependent on them being in that brand
and then they have to keep secrets and
have to like
not let this the truth out and try to to
keep
which stops them from evolving and stops
their actual
yeah anyway i'll let you share a bit and
then we can have an
open couple i was always somebody that
kind of would
you know be open to listening because i
always
you know in my own experience you know
i always felt like there was something
better and
um i got to a point in my life i'm not
going to go into the details because
it's probably for a different topic at
another point if that happens
but i was at a point where i was just
kind of trying to
grab any voice that i could resonate
with and
i found i was a lot you know finding a
lot of different things you know you'd
already mentioned
um you know tony robbins and he's
somebody who's
stuff sounds very you know
sounds solid to me but
if this makes sense his voice wasn't one
that i could hear
because i could see
you know what he's saying but i'm also
seeing videos of him in his
you know house carved into a mountain in
fiji
and i'm like you know him doing all this
like stuff i'm like
this guy does not understand what
this dude in an apartment in
massachusetts is going
he can't see me he can't feel me
so i would kind of keep going and i kind
of would try different
avenues and then i ran into um
you know the one we were discussing and
i'm
totally okay saying his name by the way
i wasn't trying to not say his name
it's all right so all right so yeah so i
you know
i think neither of us are big enough he
can even sue us so
have fun with that so yeah and
but what i what i found was
you know he wasn't necessarily
reinventing the wheel
i could hear any of his stuff he's kind
of basically it's a combination of
you know wayne dyer or byron katie
uh there's some tony in there um yeah
some michael beckwith you know any of a
few of those
you know instant faces but
what clicked to me is he spoke to me in
my
two you know in my two best languages
sarcasm and analogy
and that that was the hook
and for me it was you know
not only was it that but then i started
finding you know communities of
you know other people that were involved
in his work and a lot of it was more
not so much that i felt like i needed to
invest more in him even though i
you know went to two retreats and i went
to
you know the big event he had the dolby
i you know flew cross country for that
and it was really a lot more to connect
with the people that i had met in the
so it was kind of you know so it was
that whole experience and before
everything kind of went you know
kapow i found
things weren't necessarily
you know i don't do well staying in the
same place very
long anyway and i think this kind of
worked to my advantage here
and i found that you know
there were things being says like oh
meditate for four hours a day and i'm
like
no i can't do that because then i'm just
some
you know i'm just some bums sitting in
my car
on the beach for four hours a day
there's like
yeah meditation is good and you kind of
have to find your own way with things
like that but
you also actually have to do things it's
not
things aren't going to magically come to
you it's not like
um dream job dream vacation dream
everything come
to me um you kind of have to get out of
your own way and do your own
and really kind of do your own work
and that's where and that's where
ultimately people don't
i didn't understand it and i think a lot
of people still don't
and it's kind of designed it's
like you know it's a business it's a
gazillion dollar business and like any
other business
it's designed so that you need them when
ultimately a lot of these voices that
are out there and i'm not gonna go and
throw everybody on the bus and say that
they're all
like there's a lot of very good voices
to be heard out there
but it feels like
their voices and they can you know tap
into the thing you can't tap into
yourself
but they're not doing the work for you
they're just opening the portal for you
so you can go and do your own work and
sit in your own stuff
and re you know reframe your own
experience
and i think you know a lot of us don't
see that they see you know
the external validation
and you know we all want to be loved
we all want to be seen for who we are
that's not a bad thing
what happens is we just you know
we hear what we want to hear and we we
hold on for dear life
even though you know everything is kind
of you know an experience
and ultimately you know the whole
thing's a journey this you know
and you know this is just another stop
you know
you know you hit you know la and las
vegas
and phoenix and you know
what we don't realize what happens is we
kind of get caught in that
validation from other people that have
and
it kind of turns into a in a lot of ways
a cult mentality
it's not intended to be that way i'm not
saying
oh this person is a cult leader no
but we kind of turn it into that
sometimes because
validation is a strong sob you know
and so we kind of stay there when
ultimately
it's a step for us to go to the next
thing
yeah yeah some of the things that were
coming up for me
uh one of the things with tony robbins
kyle sees ken wilbur
people who who i've followed and then
have fallen from grace in my mind
um in real ways reality uh they
there's something about like feeling
like you need to throw the baby out with
the bathwater
and i don't it's like no actually those
truths came from inside of me
and so i'm allowed to keep the truths
and i don't need to throw it all out at
the same time
the fact that we look to people who kind
of have that tony robbins quality who
kind of have a island right and they're
like well i was poor for a week
in three decades ago so i understand
your struggle
you can't understand that struggle three
decades on like you really can't because
you're not poor right now
and you're not and it's beyond that
because then there it becomes the metric
on whether or not you're successful
if your body isn't 100 healthy than your
failure
if you're not getting richer and getting
your dream job you're a failure instead
of like i said looking at okay if a
thousand people
actually follow tony robbins program how
many of them
are happier in a year how many of them
are more rich
how many of them are healthier because
if you just pick the people who got
healthier and more rich
and then make everyone else feel like a
failure you're actually hurting the very
industry
you're in and yet there is a truth to
you need to do your own work
you can't just attend seminars and hear
about going to the gym and hear about a
diet you have to actually
do it but following my own internal
guidance that i did learn
from kyle sees in a really real way
is the powerful piece that i'm not
willing to throw out
and now it's like oh i have more
discernment
for all of it like it's like okay is
this resonate with me
and i do get upset
that people think they're not doing it
right
if their body is in pain or their
disability doesn't go away or they
aren't miraculously able to find a house
and pay off their mortgage
and especially in the coaching industry
right like how many
people in the coaching industry that's
their business they start their own
coaching business
that's not a sustainable model right
like we can't all be coaches and all
have co clients
we're all just giving each other
thousands of dollars and that's not
actually
it creates change but not really like
it's
whereas i feel like there is a way to
have
the positives without the negatives and
that will be you know more of the next
section
but uh yeah there's
this what was mentioned like the hustle
culture that it's go go go go go
and that's the only acceptable way and
someone like tony robbins i'm like yeah
you have 80 hours of work in you
i have 10. and i am finding my most
powerful way to contribute in the world
and i feel good about that and it
doesn't look like money and health
it looks like happiness though real true
happiness from the inside that i
couldn't sell to anyone else
you know i can't sell you to you know
look at my life it's like
no it's not pinterest worthy it's
amazing though what they don't
understand is there's a
value in being able to
you know build your boundaries so that
you know okay you might still be in that
same
job that you've been in but you're not
taking the crap from
your co-workers or your customers or
your
management as personally you're able to
you know take whatever information
you know is helpful but filter out the
garbage that comes with it
like that is so much more important
than even having like the you know
millions because you know
that's the the high-powered job and the
big bank account one thing we have you
know that's one thing that
is so we can learn from coronageddon
over here
that something can go south outside of
your
control and that's gone tomorrow
but if you're if you're more grounded
and your boundaries are held
and you have more expectations of the
people around you
and you're not putting up with you know
unnecessary
that doesn't belong to you
the rest of it that you start learning
okay
the financially things went wrong but i
know i have enough to build it back up
again
i know i can you know i might have lost
this front because they hold
boundaries but i know that when the next
people in my life come along
i know what to look for and what to not
look for and
that stuff gets so underrated and it's
so much more important
again it's the journey it's not
we pull ourselves to think it's the
destination but
no and exactly and so then we look for
the destination right the riches the
this instead of like
actually it's the journey there's
something about being that guru being
that
that cult leader even if that's not what
you're trying to do but then there's a
community that forms around you and then
you have to continue doing your brand
instead of actually evolving and
changing
in whatever way you want to or feels
called to
and then it's like you actually even if
your message is
questioned even if your message is the
internal part
because the community's surrounding that
that entity
um needs it to look a certain way
they're not going to let you either
right if you're like wait that doesn't
sound right right then it's like oh then
you need to not be here
it's like no isn't it supposed to be
about questioning i mean very much
kyle says he meditates for two hours a
day
who can meditate for two hours a day
that is a lot of time and then it turns
out actually he doesn't meditate for two
hours a day
he's sitting there texting you know well
between back and forth until we feel
inadequate because we're not
meditating for two hours a day and we're
not getting his money and connections
but he is because he's meditating two
hours a day no
because he's faking medi meditating two
hours a day
and i'm not saying he never meditates
but like just that lack of integrity
is like right there was something in me
that said you can't meditate two hours a
day in fact even meditating
my meditations walking in nature and
listening to my thoughts and the
movement with my body
and so allowing that that's mine and
it's like that's
allowed to be it's allowed to be what
emerges as opposed to what it
should be and mine is
you know what i get more out of
finding a cool spotify playlist putting
out a blast
and going for a drive then i do sit in
you know you know it's sitting in a
corner but and the thing is we all have
you know there is no one way to do
anything you got to find you know
it's just me and it's your way it is my
way and for every person that this all
is a different way and that's no
that's the beauty of it really
yeah and so we're at around the 15
minute mark turns out we could talk for
a few minutes about this
so now we switch over into talking about
our
individual versions of a beautiful
future what what could the self-helping
industry look like that maybe didn't
look like what we've been talking about
for the last 15 minutes what would we
want it to look like for our lives for
the world and they don't need to match
we don't need to agree on it
but we probably will because this is
kind of an area
but we don't need to um
see this is a good one that i'm kind of
you know we've talked a little bit about
this
you know off camera and i've been
struggling with i trying to build my
own brand i'm an author i do some
speaking i'm in the middle
of the process of you know rebooting a
um podcast
slash you know live stream similar to
what you have going on
and um what i found myself
in is i find myself getting into those
ruts of all these you know dropping
these little nuggets
and you know you know
sometimes it it's easy people lap it up
and like you know
you know i can't why i mean yo look we
all love
you know we all love you know hearing
the feedback
but i'm not
i'm not growing i'm kind of spitting in
the same
circles i was been in for two years
and what i'm passionate about is
actually
getting myself more out into the world
actually communicating with people and
you know i'm not
you know whether they're in like these
you know
self-help or spiritual circles i could
give two shits about that everybody's
got their you know the battles
everybody's got their stories
everybody's got their
you know survival tales and
you know they people don't give
themselves enough credit for the
goods the amazing stuff that they've
done
you know i don't have to agree with you
know i don't have to share their
background i don't have to agree with
you know their political mentality or
how they go about
their day but i can sit in appreciation
of the work that they've done and what
they've come back from
and i think a lot of that really needs
to be highlighted and i think
in that process instead of just
listening to me
you know with catchphrase after
catchphrase
i feel like there's more there's just as
much value in
you know sharing people's stories and
what they've come from and how they've
done it
and what's worked and what's failed
miserably
and they've had to turn around and come
back from i think
people will see you know what people
will see
you know in different parts people
that's me
this that i have lived this same
experience and i can do all this
you know and there's also a factor of
like there's so many different
you know people out there that do have
all these skills
and talents and all these other things
that have helped them and they used to
help others
and you know i really tend to think
life's like a
big buffet table in a lot of ways you
know what
take the you know take the kung pao
chicken leave the crab rangoons you know
and there's so many there's no one way
to do everything and
you know people are gonna you know you
know somebody might you know fall in
love with
you know eft other people might fall in
um now more of a meditation-based
practice and there's all these you know
some people are going to find what they
need through changing their
diet maybe following you know maybe
you know veganism is there
outlet or you know there's so many
different
no there's no one answer and i think
that's i think kind of
what i would love to have is you know
you know create more of a
portal where you know people can kind of
you know
look around and see what resonates
instead of following me like i'm just a
guy i
you know every so often like i have like
a good idea here and there but
what i say i know it's not gonna you
know it doesn't resonate to everybody
and
it shouldn't because you know not
everybody's gonna res
i don't resonate to what a lot of people
have to say
why should i feel entitled to have them
all resonate to me
yeah thank you it's beautiful um my idea
of
a world where self-help is is
looks better it's hard to do any of
these because they all kind of
intertwine so it's like well if we don't
have
to work and we don't like if we have our
food and our needs met and everything
else then we don't need to look
to tony robbins and pay him thousands of
dollars right it is just that portal to
like what it what
it is but if that's not there i think
there are still beautiful ways that we
can do the self-help industry
honor that there are people who want
growth and i love what you said in the
beginning that people just want to be
seen
and like loved and seen for who they are
and
that if we can honor that instead of
putting it on a guru
actually just sit with each other and
see each other and like
even if if there's something about you
that might trigger me
then that's my learning right and so i
can go sit with other people but it
doesn't make you wrong and it doesn't
make me wrong for needing to necessarily
do that
that there's a way to make sure that
nobody falls through the cracks
that no matter where you are you can ask
for help and not
have to shell out a ton of money in
order to
be able to get that help especially when
you're in poverty or sick or
it's like well yeah well if this isn't
if this is a priority it's like actually
no my next meal is a priority
and so i'm not less than because i can't
afford these things
and so having peer-to-peer like i feel
like there's something about
you when you truly need help there is a
medical community and there's flaws in
that
solution raising on suicide but having
so there's like psychiatry and
therapists and stuff that are like when
you really need help they're the ones
who are supposed to be there then you
have coaches
and even like kyle c's tried i think
somewhat to do what you're talking about
but failed miserably right where it's
like well repair it appears so it's okay
i'm not your coach we're here so
it's okay if i sleep with clients it's
okay if this happens it's okay if i
because i'm evolving too i'm just a
little boy but he's charging thousands
of dollars right
if he wasn't charging money eliminates
the peer-to-peer because
people are picking up five figures to
have these experiences
yeah and his he needs that money right
he's built a team on it he's built a
family on it and so then he can't even
see he's got the blinders on
that like he's hurting people and he's
like
you kind of can't do it in this way
unless or maybe you can maybe there is a
way we can do it
but the more we can figure out how to
get our needs met
i have um a
bit of a self-help thing that i've
created which is just internal for me
and i'm like yes i think the i love your
idea of a portal being able to find
things i have these five questions that
i'm like every
they're never answered and it's the
journey to answering them at deeper and
deeper levels it gives its own payment
like its own reward
and there's no cost just find people and
answer the five questions it's who am i
who are my people what is my purpose
whether that's in the moment or overall
arching
it's like the verb right which is what
am i supposed to be doing what do i need
and what am i really ready to let go of
and
none of them are answered i mean who am
i
right changes daily and it's like i
uncovered a deeper and deeper level who
are my people where do i feel at home
what makes me happy what makes my heart
sing right
not sit down and meditate for two hours
where do you feel close to your god
where do you feel close to your spirit
do that if it's singing if it's dancing
do that right like what does your body
want to do
and helping people tap into their own
inner wisdom
is teaching them how to fish instead of
making them dependent on your fish
market
and if the self-help industry is a fish
market right it's like well i'm just
turning everyone into fish markets like
everyone and there's like right there's
not enough
need for that but there's absolutely a
need for everyone to be seen and heard
and there's a need for us to get our
physical needs met right our food our
clothing our shelter
and there's also a lot of time and
energy like how many coaches
can make a living at it very few and
then we look at the ones like kyle cease
and tony robbins like well they're
doing good why can't we get in on that
it's like
there's not enough there's not enough of
a base in order for us to do that but i
think there are ways that we can come
together and get our needs met
because the other thing is then the
people who are coaching like i don't
want to do it for money i want to help
people
and those people are like oh well you
haven't dealt with your issues on money
right you you're not healed it's like no
no
this happens time and time again because
people who are drawn into this or either
drawn into it for money or to help
and why can't we focus on the ones that
want to help why can't we focus on how
do we get your needs met as a coach or
helper without requiring you start a
business
make a brand do you know like just sit
with people and talk and still have your
food your community everything done and
that's where it is
it is all interconnected that we need
more of what you need right and that's
also part of what you come up and
sitting with yeah and i think i really
think that that's probably
the next level however that looks like
i think you know as people kind of fall
into that
and they see you know the power of
connection the power of being seen
and they feel so
it fills them and they want so
desperately to
bring that to other people
and yeah of course we're not all
you know you know completely whole in
the process like whole
is just not a thing that exists it every
you know
that you're always there's always going
to be other layers and you know those
questions
are you know i i you know i got
having to take a look at them and saw
them and playing around with them myself
i am in love with them because
exactly as you said you can never
completely answer
and as you grow those answers those
the responses are gonna change the
places where you get
stuck trying to answer them
change and that's just as important as
the answers
yeah and being able like
if you can find a group of people who
just see you a little bit more than they
the last people saw you right and you
have a little bit more purpose
like every level pays for itself and if
you aren't paying anything out to get
access to because it's in you
all we can do is help each other right i
don't have an access to who you are only
you do
but i if i want you to get there then i
might be able to you know have a
conversation about how i found
more of who i am and
finding the portals that are more
peer-to-peer and the things that aren't
peer-to-peer and sometimes do cost money
right eft and those kind of things
um who's the best right who's in it just
for the money and who's in it for the
purpose
and how do we keep the good ones
in in business by sharing that with each
other right
so
we're nearly at the half an hour mark so
we can switch over to the um
unless you have any closing thoughts on
this one we'll switch over to the next
part
all right we can shift all right so the
next part is the adjacent possible so
it's what we could actually create
now if we had ten thousand people and a
hundred thousand dollars
so instead uh like if you had ten 000
people who were
self-help refugees from the tony robbins
and kyle cease and they were like we
want peer-to-peer right we don't want to
find a new guru we want a peer-to-peer
that's that's or whatever you think i
mean i guess it could be ten thousand
coaches who get together also and figure
out how can we
get our needs met while giving ourselves
to the world right
ten thousand what could we create with
ten thousand people at a hundred
thousand dollars
and in this space specifically i think
people are willing to give out a lot of
money
so ten dollars or ten dollars per month
is actually a very feasible thing
if they saw the value in it and it
wasn't around one central body
okay let me throw some you know a couple
of ideas that
i hadn't in my head and you know a lot
of it involves
okay these involve skill i probably
involve help and
with skills that i don't have to make it
work
but you know there's you know you know a
web presence why can't
you know we build like uh you know
you could have like a you know big
you know web community and
you know some of it can be you know in
terms of a blog or a video or things
like that where people can kind of
you know share what they you know share
what they offer
or share their own experiences through
they can tell their own stories
or explain what their process is you
know kind of like a
coach's corner for lack of a better
word and you can have something like
that but also have like a portal where
creatives can feel safe in
you know presenting what they have to
offer if they're a writer or an artist
or a musician
and be able to you know
have a positive community where they can
start to share their own
please you know and from there maybe you
know
have like a you know kind of a reddit
style
um you know a community of
you know talk spaces uh like a forum
where you know people of different
you know share like their own talk about
their own beliefs or
if they're like local like say somebody
you know
all right you're from what vancouver
correct
okay so say all right people from
vancouver
yeah were very interested in kind of
connecting and building their own
you know experience local and i think
there's you know and that kind of takes
me into like you know the other part of
that
is you know people kind of getting
together
locally even if it's just getting
together doing like a you know good deed
for somebody like go on and you know
clean up
find it's a way to like bond and then
you know
as you're kind of going and wanting to
explore your own juice you know
hey you know hey i've got this skill
that i can use to help you out
you've got this skill that can help me
out and we all kind of you know kind of
help each other along the
path and this you know i feel like
there's a couple of different
you know i feel like that's
you know the type of thing you know you
can kind of go and build upon
and it also leaves
room so that different
collectives can kind of go their own way
it's not like
you know the rich way or the jubilee way
or
any other way like it you know
as they collect connect they they build
their own way
i love an idea of like having to be able
to map out my own journey both so i can
see it and also share that with other
people right to say hey
i love the idea of a podcast to share
something along the lines of um
hey here's what worked for me here's
what didn't work for me right like
and especially the more ridiculous it is
the better right like for me
part of my journey towards happiness was
giving up on
diet and exercise in a big way and i'm
like actually i'm much happier now and
now it's starting to come in where i
want to eat better food and i want to
move my body in a certain way and it
came from internal instead of this need
to
it should look like this and that's not
something i would tell other people
right eat like and stop exercising
but it was what i needed to do right
it's like don't meditate go for a walk
in the forest no that's actually what i
need to do doing that every morning is
like that's exercise and it fills my
soul
um i love doing something at
peer-to-peer
there's a ted talk by a woman called
barbara shear
who i don't know if you're the wish
obstacle and she recently died
unfortunately
but yeah only a few weeks ago or maybe
my timeline might be a couple months ago
um
and the idea of just being able to say
right here's what's stopping me
all i need is this thing and having it
broadcast to people who have that thing
would be so powerful and it's not
reliant on one person saying whether
you're worthy or not or crowdfunding
around the campaign it's just like hey
i need advice on marketing or i can do
this thing and someone's like oh yeah i
got five minutes or you know
an hour i can give you advice on
marketing anything that it is right that
i love her big ones and the ted talk
like a horse ranch
i was like what parents are retiring you
can like i'll put you in contact with
them they have a whole friend somebody
was able to dance with patrick swayze or
something like that
yeah but you're like so and then yeah we
could uplift them right be like hey
patrick
if you were gonna dance with someone
right pick this person who of course
he's not here anymore either but
if i reshare now can be dancing with
with but patrick shrazy
and finding ways to uplift each other
and to be
in that space like i know that the best
thing i can do for myself is concentrate
is do who am i what are who are my
people but it doesn't stop there because
i can also see that i'm then able to
give more
and so if i want the world to give more
like people who know who they are in any
way
people who are connected to people who
can see them and hear and and love them
as they are
in any way like it doesn't have to be
grandiose we accept everything about you
it doesn't have to be you know yourself
down to the cell it's like
a little bit more knowing a little bit
more purpose a little bit more
my needs aren't met right oh wait i
don't have food you know like
how do we grow food together or how do
we distribute food together
and it feels so daunting because it's
all of it all at once
but the beauty is your things if we
truly
interconnect them right like someone's
purpose when they're
when they're set free of what they're
currently doing is to figure out how do
we feed
everyone someone's purpose is to figure
out how we have enough transportation
and so putting those connections
together
is like it's everything
like every big you know people talk
about these big leaps but
ultimately every big leap is really just
a series of small steps
we just don't you know sometimes they
just
you know they seem really insignificant
in the moment
but you find when you get to that other
place like
that little shift that i had on june
12th
was so much more of a game
changer than i thought it was you know
it just seemed like an annoyance at the
time but holy smokes
yeah i mean this path proves itself
there's like
something parallel like self-help when
he talks about in that video
of like the toxicity where just like the
people who are drawn to it they don't
love themselves right like it's like
i want to improve kind of means you
don't accept yourself as you are
but there's a beautiful path that's very
close and parallel
of i love myself as i am and even if i
can't i love that i can't do that yet
and through that love and acceptance of
ourselves and
then you start loving and accepting more
people for who they are truly
including their shadow including their
their issues
like it builds on itself as an
individual as a group
as a globe the more we know ourselves
the more we're connected with each other
the more we're doing work that we feel
good about whether that's cleaning up a
garden bed
or starting a food cooperative or
anything like if you can find people and
work on projects with
then that's huge and so having something
that just connects people
the simple website right something like
my five questions or
or maybe that's too narrow because your
five questions are different
right but having something simple to
begin with and then having a brand show
like actually you know what
i've and i've had people say like what
my what's my purpose is way too big
i want like what am i doing right now
like what's a verb right
and it's like okay yeah and who am i is
some it's way too big of a question
like what do i want for dinner you know
what brings me happiness right now
and and mapping that out and figuring
out
how other people have figured out who
they are can i follow those paths and if
they're
um costly how can we work together to
bring them down because there's also
like working one-on-one with a coach is
expensive for a lot of reasons
but there's ways that the coach can be
like okay you know what if i have five
clients for the hour
i can charge twenty dollars i'm making a
hundred dollars but they're each
charging 20.
right or they're each paying 20. well
that's more accessible for everybody
right they're still getting money and if
it's done in a way where they don't have
to market constantly
there's people who are being drawn into
them then
we can get coaches needs met and meet
people where they are in their financial
lives
right like okay 25 an hour to talk to
somebody who
is worth hundreds of dollars an hour
yeah okay i'm gonna value it cause i'm
putting in 25
and i'm going to get a community of
people who are meeting at that same time
around that coach maybe but those were
two different peer-to-peer and coaching
and having seminars like this is this is
kind of a really interesting place
because there's so many people in this
space
right tony robbins i mean kyle cease has
10 000 people
i'm pretty sure like his page and follow
him on youtube tony robbins has millions
and the issue is finding the parallel
path that we want
and then bringing people together and
saying what do we create together
that we want right that isn't focused on
that doesn't mean you have to
let go of tony robbins or kyle cease or
anybody else
right because you can bring those into
the space you can say hey this person
is who i learned this from and maybe it
doesn't resonate with me because it's
that person so maybe someone else is
like oh you know what someone else does
something very similar listen to this
person
and that's actually one of the one of
the actual i think
perks of why having so many
people in the field is a lot of times
you know like they're not again they're
not reinventing the wheel here there's a
lot of
but different people have different ways
of saying the same thing so
if you know gabby bernstein says it one
way
that that really clicks to you
score other people are gonna you know go
back
to you know say like an old you know
wayne dyer
video and he might say it a little bit
different probably not very different
because she's
you know very much a disciple hits but
he may say something in a little
different way that okay
bam that resonates and that you know
that's actually
you know one of the beauties of
the field because you know yeah as much
as there are a lot of
you know issues there are there is a lot
of
you know good that comes from having all
these different voices
absolutely and even from
like there's those the people who are
more of the coachy coach people right
who would be more names that you would
know but there's also like mining yours
interpretation of them
right that even that might be something
that resonates more with someone rather
than someone else right it's not
necessarily about
creating a huge base of listeners but
like hey if what i have to say resonates
more with someone than the original
speaker
i want them to get it in the way they're
going to hear it right so
the less ownership we can have over the
ideas as well i mean i don't even know
where half of my ideas come from both
like the ones that have come from inside
of me i
don't know where do those things come
from and the ones that something magical
some super subconscious thing
and but the ones that i'm like i know i
learned this somewhere
but i don't know how to attribute it
back like even if i'm like oh i learned
this from ken wilbur i learned this from
kyle sees
i don't know where they learned it from
right so and they're not going to every
time they say it say where they learned
it from
or even if they did it's not going to
register in my brain yeah
and so it's what are the tools what are
the tools for me to get to know myself
how do
i get happier how do i find more purpose
and the more that we can i think start
those conversations the better i mean
that was originally
the idea behind the um life after kyle
c's facebook group
wasn't to get together and discuss kyle
cease it was like how do we actually
create something that is coaching
without
a leader but i think there's too many
people in the space who want to be
coaches so they don't even like they
don't even know how to
shift in that way and they're that's
fine right like it's like okay
it's a different space but there is
something important that could be
created
sorry i'd say that's probably part of
the process yeah
absolutely i mean you maybe do need two
or three coaches to fall from grace to
be and that was like with what happened
with kyle
it became very self-evident to me that
i surpassed him long ago like it was
like and i didn't know that until he
fell i was like oh i know i'm not
meditating two hours a day but neither
is he and that's not even the point
i show up in an authentic way and
present myself on camera like he's good
at what he does he has
a better speaking voice he doesn't i'm
in awe all the time he has the words he
has the humor
but i'm showing up in a way that's like
right i don't have that and i'm still
showing up
right and that's actually bigger it's
like i'm actually doing the work i'm
actually the apple tree putting out the
apples
and it and not to put him down but it's
like also i don't have his life i don't
need to pay people
and get you know what i mean i don't
have employees that rely on me i don't
have i have a daughter but i'm not
her future doesn't look a certain way
when i'm in the limelight versus out
right like it's like no
and i feel bad for him because he's not
living his own ideals like i'm like i
don't think you can evolve from this
space when you're hiding when you're
like oh no no we can't talk about that
we've moved on we've moved on it's like
no you're in the like you're not letting
people shine a light on it you're not
shining a light on it
and i feel bad like i'm like you need
you need something yeah your dog agrees
yeah that's cheap animals
animals you know
i can tell them no but it's just
yeah it's funny it's nothing to do with
self-help but like things like cat cafes
and dog places to just go and be like
be around animals that you don't
necessarily have to take care of they
can have
interactions with is healing all in of
itself to be able
amazon just dropped off a package
and his favorite snack is the amazon guy
i know i know i know
that's all right good old dogs
cats horses like horses is one of the
ones i want to have access to but i have
no
amount of knowledge to have a horse or
money or anything else but to be able to
go and be with them
is is amazing and to be able to connect
with nature
and know i have this amazing experience
in this community i'm part of
this guy's i don't know what his action
he he went to um
he's like a preacher by trade i don't
not a preacher but like went to building
whatever school to me and
he he so they go to church as a family
and i don't
and one of the things i said to him is i
was like my church my equivalent would
be going singing in nature with people
and he's like oh yeah my friend does
that
like i was like how perfect that this
person who i thought would have not like
that's not church right like that's not
your
was like oh yeah one of my friends does
that like they go different places in
the lower mainland
every week this is long before
copenhagen and they sing in nature
it's like yes that's what i want but to
be able to say that right to be able to
say hey here's what i want and either
start a group around it or someone can
lead you there
and say actually that's already going on
in your space and even if it's nothing
to do with self-help right it's like oh
i want to play soccer i want to learn a
musical instrument i want to do that
it all comes in because it's i think
it's even better because it's like
coming from inside like i want to learn
how to use
play a guitar not this guru plays guitar
and said i was supposed to learn how to
play guitar so i
should learn to play guitar like no do
you want to
is that a call to you how do we get you
a guitar how do we get your lessons
how do we actually help you do that in a
way that's
integral to you yeah and that's so
and i think that's kind of what you know
i think that's going to be the next
steps to people they you know
i think in a lot of ways like a lot of
the you know the natural
progressions i you know they want to do
all this stuff so they feel like
all right they need to you know coach me
to teach
if you know it's not necessarily working
because
it's a should and they haven't figured
it out yet but
as they kind of you know evolve within
then you know maybe it is that okay
instead of doing it this way
maybe i'm kind of you know maybe doing
you know more of a storyteller like
we'll bring in the guitar
you know what you know maybe it feels
right to just you know really kind of
learn the guitar
or or ukulele or whatnot and just real
i can kind of you know you know kind of
speak about it and kind of do it in like
song
or maybe even do it for kids i mean oh
my
gosh how much value would there be in
having like uh
you know like somebody that you know
plays kids songs
with those kind of messages and getting
and having you know kids kind of learn
that instead of some of the hard wiring
most of us
learn that tends to you know shoot us in
the foot down the road how much
value would be in that and this
and that's just one you know this
infinite
you know infinite possibilities yeah
and the diversity of like what the
individual needs like you kind of need
that buffet
like you need to have a a tray of like
here's what it is and the more that we
can come together and create that
then the more we can honor that it's
there's nothing wrong with the tony
robbins and kyle ceases
but also because part of it also is like
his youtube channel
you can't comment on there with like
everything goes through him so the
things aren't coming to light
which also is like stopping his own
growth right like it's like oh no no my
new people who are paying me money can't
find out about that old thing that's
that's that's over
and if he had just let it happen
it would be over by now like i don't
think people would still be seeking him
out and be like you
because he didn't do anything absolutely
horrific that he needs to be canceled
forever
but he did something horrible that he
needs to own and actually apologize for
not do one
apology video or just own and be like
right i'm not that's my life and i'm not
apologizing for it i've acted in the
moment
but keeping it in the dark is like
oh it's hurting you and i can see in my
life where those things happen and that
is like the biggest learning is the
reflection on the outside is inside
all of the learning opens up because
it's like every time i have an issue
with anyone or anything
it's like okay what am i learning from
this what can i learn
and then you start to really enjoy life
and the roller coaster of learning
you're like oh another fall from grace
of a coach what is there to learn here
how interesting like it honestly wasn't
devastating to me it was shocking
but it wasn't devastating because it was
like oh yeah these things happen he's a
human being and
bad things happen and then everyone goes
on board and this is like again my
judgment so i'm sure there's something
here to learn
of like oh i always knew he was a bad
guy or i always knew i had a weird
feeling about him i'm like well why
didn't you act on it then
like why like now with hindsight i'm
like i didn't i thought he was a great
guy i still think he's he's a good human
being who
90 is probably in alignment and the 10
is gonna him over
and that's what he needs like i'm like
that's lit the universe will give him
exactly what he needs i don't need to go
out of my way to
like try to you know like him over
because the universe
has our back like it's like and that's
the beauty also is
is has his back
right like the universe is here to teach
me exactly what i'm here to learn
and everybody else as well and so if i'm
focused on everybody else
i'm not paying attention to like my
lesson i signed up for
all the money i paid for this life to be
like okay this
is my lesson yeah and that's the thing
it always comes back around
like if you try to bury it it comes back
in a different form
and it was you know you know kind of
watching the process on my end because i
stuck around to see what he would do and
you know i saw the
you know apology and i just you know i
stuck around for a couple of more and it
was just kind of like
we're going to pretend you know we're
just going to pretend nothing happened
nothing to see here la la la and it
wasn't even i you know i
it wasn't like i got angry or offended
or anything like that it was just kind
of like okay
this is where right this is where the
train gets out now
yeah and i walk out i go do something
else like i kind of you know
i've written about it and you know i
left names out of it because i don't
really
i don't care to deal with lawyers and i
just kind of like hey look this is kind
of where i was at and i kind of wanted
to tell
you know my experience i posted that and
from there it's like you know some
people
decided all right well if you're going
this way then you know i don't need to
fall you know be friends with you
anymore and you know i wish them well
and other people you know and
you know it's all okay and i've gotten
to the point where i've
completely i i don't remember wednesday
nights anymore it's like
you know like i might see somebody post
something on facebook like oh i got this
great i'm like
oh yeah it's wednesday
i haven't i went to one of his events in
l.a
um and i've bought his books other than
that
and i bought a few of the courses that
were online like before i went to the
events in l.a but i don't pay the e then
the monthly fee i did until i didn't pay
the
extreme amounts that other people paid
who also were sleeping with it like it's
like that is the complete disconnect
from like why are you charging them and
sleeping with them that seems very wrong
but anyway side note um
that having i forgot where i was going
oh i was kind of out of the community
when it happened anyway like i was
already like i learned what i
was meant to learn from this guy i've
moved on to other teachers that resonate
with me more but i still will come back
every once in a while like he had his
money book and i read it
and nothing that the quote just say
about money kind of resonates because it
always is like this inside healing i'm
like
money's evil i'm sorry like it's like oh
well that's your healing i'm like no
i know way too much about economics and
capitalism for you to be able to
spiritually
strong army into like this is this is
the path and i don't judge other people
who feel it is because i want them to
have money and success so they can do
their mission on earth
but that's not where mine's coming from
and
yeah i don't remember where i was going
your eyes tend to tell you yeah their
eyes tell you something different
absolutely so what do you think is the
most powerful thing
in your mind that we could do with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars
maybe something we talked about or
something that comes new
all right how do we
you know i think ultimately it's
creating a you know it comes down to
you know how it's done whether it's
physical whether it's web you know
it's irrelevant there's different a
million ways to do it how do you create
a platform where those 10 000 people
um can see for themselves what they're
capable of
and use that platform to launch
themselves
i think ultimately that's
that's what you know
needs to happen and then
you know because ultimately you want to
have
you you know in my mind it's like
how do i get them to find themselves and
how do i get them to not need me anymore
yeah yeah what i was going to say which
was the thing with kyle sees i wasn't on
the calls but when they fell apart i was
like why don't you guys all just host
calls together
like why do you need him because when i
was on calls with him
he answers like one of a thousand
people's question right like i was like
oh well he's not answering my question
and even when he does answer them like
it's not
sometimes it resonated with me and
sometimes it didn't but it was like you
know what i want is i actually want to
talk about his work
with other people i don't want rather
than watching him and hoping he answers
my question
because if he's not answering your
question then why watch it live right
why not just
watch it as broadcast yeah because and
so content is there you're paying for
access
yeah yeah and so but what i want is
peer-to-peer to discuss about
in that case calego right or discuss um
the apple tree like what is coming up
for me and my work doing this
peer-to-peer so that we can see and hear
each other
and and i think having something similar
to that
even for the coaches that exist whether
they you know
and doesn't matter how good or bad they
are in the moment uh
i mean it does but having one place
where their work can be
and they don't have to be there right
you can just say hey i'm a teal swan fan
i'm a kyle cease fan and then find
people to talk about their work with
seems like it would meet people exactly
where they are which they're not where
we are right they're not necessarily
looking for peer-to-peer
but would get so much value out of it
and if it was free right because you're
just saying hey do you like teal swan
come and talk to people who like to swan
you're not it doesn't need to go through
her and therefore she has to okay the
message or not
it doesn't have to be on kyle cease's
eol page and no one else can say
anything bad about him because you're
gonna get kicked out
it's like because because my guess is if
it had been open and you could have
peer-to-peer conversations about it
there would have been people who having
those conversations would have left and
people who would have stayed
yeah and that would have been like out
in the open right i have less problem
with people who know about it
have dealt with it are like yeah i'm
still getting something of value here
rather than it being swept under the rug
and being like well you're if you stay
then you're go
oh you're not my friend i'm like i no
as long as you're okay that i'm not
following him anymore that's
you know that's a big discussion for
another forum of course
but that's just kind of the world
reflecting with that stuff
yes um a few of us actually after the
dolby
um because i guess there was like a
thing where they did like the you know
201 call or whatever the thing they did
with
with kyle and a few of us were like
well we could instead of doing that one
of us can just get like a zoom room
and we can just connect every morning
ourselves
and just kind of talk about things and
we did that for a year
and it was actually really amazing we
got the you know we pop on
we still connect like weekly you know
like
you know two years later and we still
you know we kind of you know either work
through stuff or we kind of
tell each other hey this is the thing we
see or we'll talk about the world and
kind of what we
and we have some like really amazing
conversations and there's so much more i
think we've gotten from
stuff like that that i probably would
have gotten
just you know sitting and listening
and spending you know spending the money
on
that yeah
you didn't my guess is it didn't cost
money but even if it did right even if
you're all putting in ten dollars
a month or a session to pay for zoom or
whatever you're paying for and then have
a pool of money to spend whatever you
want
it's not thousands of dollars going to
someone who's selling you something that
they
they need to sell you so you don't know
if it's truthful you don't know what the
marketing is behind it
and i love the idea of a peer-to-peer
portal a portal
either around existing coaches or just
hey we're going to get together and goal
set we're going to get
like any we a bunch of divorced men who
just all got divorced you know here
have a self-help group a bunch of you
know single moms who
are struggling but can't leave their
house to get help because their kids are
sleeping
support group and being able to meet
constantly and then you are
figuring out you kind of are seen and
hearing each other and if
this group doesn't work for you know
where to go for a new group
and to know that you always have access
to somebody
who will who will help yeah
somebody's always there it's just a
matter of
can i in the bubble that
i have around me am i able to find
him or her or them
yeah and so being able to have a portal
that actually helps like a technology
portal right something like facebook
something like
a social media platform that is hey any
group you want to start
here's the group of people because the
10 000 right here's the 10 000 people
who are
having life events who wants to do
better or whatever their version of
self-help is
and then how do we connect you right is
it based on time is it based on someone
you follow is it based on a book you
just read
is it based on just availability let's
see let's try let's play
and figure out together what's not
working and then
keep improving it yeah and can i i know
i'm looking at the clock and i know
up against that but can i throw one more
idea that kind of
absolutely um i could see
you know people have like you know
events like say
you know have like a park for the
weekend
and you know set it up you know we have
you know different booths people who
have
you know different skills it could be
and you know or
different you know people like there are
or they're
or their you know if they you know they
do a particular kind of cooking or meal
prep or something like that
you know do all these kind of
demonstrations and then you have like on
like other stages you can have
you can have you know inspirational
speakers or you can have
or have you know musicians and kind of
you know and kind of you know have it
you know each kind of be locally based
and have
you know kind of people you know
connecting and kind of sharing their
aspects of
the story and you know people might not
necessarily come
to get you know inner
whatever out of it they may come just
because
hey it's a saturday afternoon and
you know i got some time to kill um you
know let's take this
you know my partner and go and
explore and you know you can start
getting you know exposed to ideas but
not
have them you know be you know shut down
your throat and then other people are
gonna see other
things you know they might see like a
you know a reiki healer and do like a
you know a trial mini session and you
know fall in love with that
or they might see somebody doing a um
you know
you know a keto demonstration or yo
maybe like yoga or something like that
and you know
it's you know it creates awareness for a
lot of people
all at once and also brings different
avenues and different venues and all at
the same time and it's local
you're not dealing with you know
keyboard warrior number 186
stop now that's like in
yeah wherever it's every you know
these are people that you can see every
day and you have access to
and actually you know build physical
connections because
i think another thing we're learning
from this stuff is
yeah we have you know a lot of online
stuff but that physical presence is
so important
i like that idea because also even if
like reiki isn't my thing
or even if it was and then it falls away
then i know that if i go to that thing
the next time i'm not
losing the whole the all of it i'm just
losing that booth
right like i can just like oh okay let's
go to this other
yeah empty booth and find that all right
we are at the hour
so we can say goodbye to youtube thanks
for hanging out rich
thank you and